hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft
and it starts off in a in a glass cage
by the looks of things
the afk display case do not feed
well that thanks for that
you can't go afk on this server for a
second well i've been thinking about
what to do this episode as the last few
have been pretty heavy on sahara i
thought
i should probably just get it out the
way there's such a small amount to do so
i think for the beginning of this
episode what we're going to do is finish
off the actual building but let me give
you a little bit of an update on what's
going on so i've been sort of hacking
away at trying to get this finished as
much as possible i've added a little bit
of detailing on the side here on this
big grey wall but i want to add a bit
more
down here we've got the shop front but
the outside of it is well there's
nothing here
there's absolutely nothing here and i
actually need to put a sign saying that
we're not open yet on the inside i'm
nearly finished with all of the
decorations where this is where the
customer is going to be this is where
they're going to interact with the shop
so this has to look nice and for the
most part i'm getting there
up here is another unfinished area
particularly with this wall that's doing
nothing in particular so that's on to
the to-do list for today we've got our
sahara hermit news over there so
i always call it sahara news it's not
saharan news it's hermit news it's a
unbiased new news broadcast so maybe
we're gonna do a bit more of that as
well
and then over here this is where the
majority of the building is like the big
warehouse building however
i'm not actually going to be touching
any of this today because iskall told me
that they're not quite sure what to do
with the redstone and it needs to go
underneath so i don't want to go and
build anything until the redstone is
finished
i have a feeling this room will be
available to me but for the most part i
just want to get the majority of the
build done so we're going to fill in
these walls we're going to do a bit of
more decoration and we're just going to
finish up everything to get it set in
stone or
probably more white concrete so let's
crack on with a time lapse to try and
get sahara done
before we move on with the rest of the
episode so what i wanted to start doing
in this time lapse is actually address
the back of the giant grey wall i
thought it would be really fun to add a
little glass feature
that allowed us on the inside to sort of
look over the shopping district which
you know eventually may become our
kingdom as sahara dominates all of the
economy of course we don't know if
that's actually going to happen we don't
even know if we're going to get a
singular customer however i am going to
do my best to market the shop and its
concept as well as i can and instead of
helping in this time lapse iskall
decided just to watch look look at him
he just just watched me do it and then
and then left
so i made that glass thick or at the
start and then i actually made it much
thinner and then i went round the back
of the sahara shop
and i just finished what was there so i
needed to fill in this last remaining
wall and the floor underneath it it
needed doing that took a long time
because despite it not taking that long
in terms of actually building it's
gathering the gravel gathering the sand
gathering the bone meal putting it all
together and then sitting in the
concrete maker so all of that stuff it
takes a long time
and that feels kind of weird because now
the outside of sahara is pretty much
finished
uh there's obviously still a lot of
interior work to do but having the
entire outside finished is a massive
achievement there are thousands and
thousands of blocks that have gone into
this enormous project
and it's very exciting to see it done
and we didn't skimp out either we went
for the the difficult blocks the
concrete the quartz it was a grind and
i'm very very happy
to say that the building is very much
finished for the exterior as you can see
though there's still a long way to go on
the inside but having finished the
exterior it means that the redstone guys
know exactly where they need to be
but after the time lapse i was just on
the server messing about as i do and you
guys know me by now i'm a little bit of
a prankster yeah i'm gonna just walk
backwards while i tell this story and uh
hopefully it'll be a little bit weird so
basically i like to mess with absolutely
everyone and anyone that's on the server
especially if they're streaming if
they're streaming i just i love popping
in and making a bit of a fuss okay and
i'm gonna tell you what i did to rendog
tv now he wasn't actually streaming at
the time but he was afk and you know how
i feel about people that go afk so i
actually started to push ren and i i
don't know where i was going with it but
he was still afk about five minutes into
me pushing him around
so i decided to start recording it
and the brilliant thing about ren is
that sometimes you can really really
trick him with the simplest of things so
i pushed him and i pushed him and i
pushed him for about 20 minutes now that
doesn't sound like a very long time but
it is when you're pushing someone in
minecraft because it's a very very
lengthy process
so i pushed him and i even had to use
slabs to get him up the hill and i kept
pushing him and pushing him and pushing
him until
he ended up
inside a cliff
outside his base now bearing in mind he
started in a little cave underground he
was just afk in his base so to get him
from down in that cave all the way up
into a random cave and he came back from
his afk session in the complete darkness
and he was so confused and about 10
minutes later he comes back and he's
like
what how did you how did you get here he
thought i teleported him in everything
he he was honestly baffled and i
absolutely found it hilarious
i pretended it wasn't me he didn't know
it was me either i tried to i tried to
blame it on someone else but anyway
that's just some of the shenanigans that
i like to get up on but this one in
particular i found really funny because
it was such oh it was just it wasn't it
wasn't meant to be an actual prank it
just ended up happening and that stuff
happens off camera all the time enough
of my story about pushing red dog around
i actually also have started another
room within sahara now this is going to
be quite important as you know in my
base we've got a meeting room the
infinity room that has been used an
awful lot in the past but we can't keep
using that for sahara matas so i've
created a board room now i'm not
finished as you can see there's still a
lot of glass that needs placing but this
is like an interior room where we can
all meet and talk about our things for
example the marketing campaign and this
is going to be a huge part of my role in
sahara
because i don't know the redstone i mean
who knows what's going on over there
really no who knows
a couple of people to be fair but not me
so my role is going to be marketing i
need to bring people to sahara which
should be a lot of fun so we've already
got the shop at sahara hashtag shop at
sahara
pretty standard stuff we've got a flyer
campaign that i'm hoping to do
targeted ads that's going to be a lot of
fun and question my question about
question mark because
i don't want to i don't want to reveal
all my secrets but basically what i'm
trying to say here is that i've got some
big plans and hopefully i can pitch
these to the guys so imagine me standing
here i'm gonna i've got my like my board
with the uh with the charts on it and
i'm gonna have to pitch my marketing
thing to the other sahara guys and also
this here is where i'm going to move the
power this is a pretty this is a pretty
terrible room to be honest with you so
i'm going to move all of these parrots
and probably get some more into here and
we can have a room dedicated to dancing
parrots while we're having our meeting
the problem is getting the parrots
is a bit of a pain because you have to
go all the way to the jungle and then
get them to tp back with you
it's a mess so we're gonna do that later
and hopefully create like a nice
uh avery here for them which should be
really really cool but we'll get on that
a little bit later on so yeah i've got
some massive plans here i'm also
planning a secret room so obviously we
can't have all of our meetings in here
some meetings have to happen
in secret so i'm hoping i can get like a
button like here
and then you press it and the floor
opens up and you fall into here everyone
all of those bits where you're standing
by those chairs they all open up with
some pistons i'm gonna have to ask mumbo
jumbo for a bit of help
and you fall down into here now this is
going to be a bigger infinity room than
the one i've got in my base and this is
going to be where we have our secret
meetings but as you guys know from my
infinity room it's a very very expensive
project because you have to make
thousands of item frames and then
thousands of maps now that's very very
expensive so that's also on my to-do
list i also realized that there's like
windows here so i'm gonna have to cover
those up somehow but yeah it's actually
really good to have some progress in
here now i can't do anything on this
side because of that as i said we don't
know where the redstone is going to go
and i imagine that all of that may end
up being used but i think this side of
the building is free game at the moment
now the next thing that we're going to
do is kind of sahara related but not
really so as you guys know there are
three people involved the architects
myself a founding member mumbo jumbo a
founding member and iskal who we invited
a bit later on now the thing about iskal
is that he really
really doesn't like a particular block
and that's diorite and i've been looking
around in every single box here there's
none he burn
all of it oh
a single block of diorite he must have
missed a bit but if you look here all of
the diorite has gone and that's because
iskal has burned it all
and that's quite impressive because
diorite is pretty common but you know me
i don't like wasting things and if
there's money to be made and there is
there's always diamonds to be made in
this in this server
then i want to see it sold rather than
burned now i'm guessing that diorite
just isn't going to be sold at sahara
purely because iskal is doing some of
the redstone
so what i've done is i've salvaged as
much as i can on the sly every time
because he's been burning it i've been
recovering it and i've managed to get a
couple of shulker boxes of diorite and
what i thought i'd do is create a little
secret shop so i can anonymously sell it
and i thought what better place to do
that than in the bird poop pile itself
now this is probably
one of my favorite things as i said
there's a little bird up there that
started around about the start of the
season and it has been just letting
loose so i thought what we could do is
not disturb this too much because this
is a work of art this truly is so what i
thought we could do is just break in a
tiny little bit just a tiny little bit
and then what we're gonna do
is we're gonna we're going to just
extend this a little bit into a little
diorite cave and anyone that wants to
buy some can come here and we can sell
it for a really really reasonable price
you know in context
this is a really horror this is probably
the most disgusting shop that has ever
been built on the server
i could even rename it to bird poop but
i don't think i am i think i'm just
going to leave it as die alright but
this is absolutely gross i just i feel
gross even though i know that this is a
rock and not bird poop
it just it just feels disgusting there
we go we are now finished just need to
do a finishing touch of adding a bit of
carpet there and yeah we've got a cave
made out of
you know
so what i've done is i've dyed both of
these shulker boxes this one's called
bird presence and this one's called bird
paint
it's not quite full but the going price
of diorite at the moment is about four
stacks for a diamond i'm going to double
that to eight eight stacks for one
diamond
this stuff would have been burnt anyway
so this is a fantastic deal if you want
to buy a whole shulker box
then it's five diamonds so there we go
this this shop is secret diorite one
diamond for eight stacks so that's at
least three diamonds in here
four five there's about five diamonds
worth that's really not a lot but i mean
this didn't take long this didn't take
long to make and it adds to that bird's
endeavors that bird's mission
to cover the shopping district in um
yeah
or it's five diamonds for the full
shulker box so obviously these shulker
boxes are worth quite a lot anyway so i
thought if you could just buy the whole
thing for five diamonds and also don't
tell iskall i i'm counting on all of you
not to give away my new secret shop
so if anyone actually manages to find
that that would be absolutely brilliant
well that takes care of that job which
i've been meaning to do for a while
because it's very hard to collect all of
that dye right on the sly you have to
understand that iskall's pretty prolific
with just going and emptying all of
these and burning them so we've got to
be really careful about it but if
there's diamonds to be made there's
diamonds to be made i think now it's
time to work on something that i'll be
honest
i hoped someone else would do i really
didn't want to have to do this but i
think it's time i need a new project
and i can't wait any longer and as you
guys know i love to fly in minecraft the
elytra is one of my favorite things and
you can catch me flying around the
district at all times pretty much and i
have my own like favorite route through
all of the weird stuff
however nobody on the server has made an
elytra flying course
and i would like to start one now this
is a huge project that's going to take a
long time to make so there's no way i
can start it and finish it in this
episode but i would like to talk about
some of the plans that i have so up on
this hill and we are just above the
stock exchange here i'm hoping to make a
platform that goes quite high up in the
air and has a platform that extends over
it now the idea is that we create sort
of like quidditch hoops that you fly
through and they ding every time and
they're numbered one two three four five
etc etc and you have to fly around it as
fast as you can but here's the twist
this is going to be a bit of a shop so
you pay a diamond to play the course if
you die then you fail and you lose the
diamond if you beat my time then you
actually win a prize and i don't know
how many that is yet but
and just before everyone gets all
concerned in the comments i've talked to
the hermits and i've asked them
every single person and they are
absolutely fine with me creating this
course and attaching it to buildings and
all sorts it's not going to look exactly
pretty okay that's that's just the way
that this is gonna go like you cannot
just make these circles and have it look
pretty however i will do my best to make
it fit in as much as possible and not
just be loads of hoops everywhere
but the idea is that we create a really
fun course people are really looking
forward to it her other hermits are
really excited to see what i can create
but there's like a bit of a problem you
see when i fly through the
uh hermitcraft shopping district i like
to go through these really difficult
tight spaces as fast as i can kind of
like this and i've got my usual spots
that i like to go through for example
one of them is straight through here
under this not particularly difficult
but then i like to turn and go through
here and then i start hitting things
but there's a bit of a problem i can't
just put the hoops
through all of these tight spaces it's
just not going to work there's not
enough space to put the hoops so i've
really really got to think very
carefully
about where each of these hoops are
going to go
so i was thinking at least it's going to
start up here on this uh platform that
extends out here so maybe roughly about
here i'm thinking it's going to go
straight down
through you've got to go up through here
and then down under this
and then carry on through here and then
that's as far as i've got so i've got a
vague oh that looks so good in the in
the distance
but i know where it's going to start and
finish i've got only a few points that i
i think will work out i need to make
sure that i'm not too intrusive so i'm
going to take my time making this i
really am i'm going to do a few hoops
per episode until the course is done the
idea is that hopefully
over the course of a few weeks
we can make a course that goes through
some of the most interesting parts of
the hermitcraft server
it's it is possible that i could make an
elytra course that goes like on the
outside of the island but i think that's
less fun especially as i really really
enjoy flying through
the actual shopping district itself
because there's so many more interesting
parts and also if you do fail the course
you die and then all your items are
right here in the shopping district so
it's not a big deal and i imagine if
this is a very fast-paced and difficult
course which is what i want to create
then it will happen quite a lot where
people take some fall damage so to get
started i really want to start by
planning out where these are going to go
i'm not going to build anything too
concrete but i'm thinking like a wooden
platform that starts up here
nothing too high for the moment
so the platform will end up being around
here
and then it's going to extend a little
bit like it's an actual like bungee jump
platform
and i'm thinking that you got to dive
down and there's immediately
a horizontal hoop
right underneath so you've got to start
by going down and then immediately pull
up
going out through here so i want this to
be a very challenging course and i need
to like create a symbol here that shows
that it's the elytra course and
hopefully we can make a bit of money by
making a really tough course now here's
the thing i have to complete this course
by myself without getting hurt as well
so i know where it's going to start
which is there on this platform that i
have not created i mean that's awful but
i also know where i want it to finish
and i think it's actually rather elegant
i want it to end right up there i want
to create a circle a really nice big
circle at the top of my base
and that way
sorry
oh
forget that is absolutely typical apps
absolutely tiff oh it's gonna be a
nightmare okay let me let me go and
repair my lightroom we'll get back to
making this elytra course
oh we're back in the air now so yeah as
i was saying
i would like the end of this to be up
here this circle like a quart circle i'm
thinking and that actually fits really
nicely in with my base since i'm going
to be sort of attaching hoops with
everybody's permission with everyone's
permission i'm going to be attaching
hoops all over the island and i'm going
to try and do it as as nicely as
possible i don't want for example to
just put a hoop right there in the
middle that you've got to fly through
let's be honest though the shopping
district
is a bit of a mess a bit of a beautiful
mess if you ask me i absolutely love
flying
quite badly sometimes through all the
nooks and crannies i think that's
probably my favorite one
i love flying through the shopping
district in general but with a proper
flying course i think i can present a
really fun challenge
so what i think we can do is start with
our very first
planning points so i'm not going to make
any actual hoops but i want to show you
the locations first so let's just make
this in wood first so that we can plan
out where this is going to be and
because we don't want to make the actual
hoops until we know that this is a good
course to do
so right this isn't going to be the way
that it actually is but there's a hoop
right here so this is the starting one
all right so this is the course so far
we're only going to do a few points so
it goes down
you gotta pull straight up through here
and then i actually want it so you got
to go round and through here so i want
to attach one
straight to this middle pillar
okay so i've made all of the plan points
i've made all of the uh temporary rings
so that we can test out the first part
of this or at least what we're going to
do in this episode so this is my current
course it goes through this one
and then down there you've got to do a
quick hairpin turn up through there and
then down so let's give this a little
test ride you know what that this
actually doesn't look that but i know
that it's just like wood rings but it
actually doesn't look that bad it
doesn't look like it's really intrusive
anyway let's give this a go shall we so
you fly through here and remember speed
is key so you've got to spam some
rockets to keep up your speed you got to
go down here through this ring you got
to travel through there i took a bit of
damage and then out the other side and
then i've got to figure out where i go
from here
but i think that's a really good
starting point i think there should be a
penalty like a time penalty every time
you take damage forcing you to try and
beat your time so like you know maybe
every every hit that you take adds five
seconds onto your time or something like
that i haven't come up with all of the
ins and outs but this should be really
fun it's not yet actually that
challenging because the
spaces aren't that difficult but i
imagine as the course goes on it will
get difficult so i did that without any
damage taken so i've really got to take
it inside some of these more difficult
turns and
really do like right angle turns and
stuff but i think this is going to be a
really fun project that is going to do
well in terms of the hermits taking it
on i think it might look actually quite
cool i was really worried about how bad
this might look but the hermits are
excited i'm excited and hopefully you
guys are excited as well to see
well it's season six first mini game i i
think i don't think anyone else has made
a proper minigame so
this will be the first one and i'm very
very excited but anyway i think that is
all we have time for today i must
apologize for the slow uploads but i'm
now back on track with things and i hope
to get some more videos out very very
soon particularly in hermitcraft and
another thing
those of you that watched my last
episode and at the end of the episode
because those of you that watch all the
way to the end you're my favorite no no
no those of you that watch all the way
to the end you guys really really do
support me a lot and i actually said at
the end of my last episode
that if you hadn't subscribed please
subscribe to my channel because i wanted
to see if it actually made a difference
and boy did it so many people more than
usual subscribed to the channel and that
felt really really good i didn't
actually think saying hey you subscribed
to my channel i didn't think that
actually worked especially when it's you
know at the start of the video so maybe
i'll i'll include it you know as a bit
of a as a side thing if you do enjoy my
videos please do consider subscribing
there's a huge amount of people that
watch this series that aren't subscribed
and it really does help the channel you
can you know get notified when i upload
a video so you don't miss it
and uh yeah oh god i i hate oh and oh
i really don't like doing all that
youtuber stuff but if you do like the
videos please consider subscribing thank
you very much for watching as always and
i'll see you guys in the next episode of
hermitcraft and hopefully i'll have some
more of this
elaborate elytra range to show you and i
hope to make this
really tough and fun
let me know what you think in the
comments and good bye
you